Guide to the New York State College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
Cornell University, New York State College of Home Economics records,
- Series I. Administration and Personnel
  - Records of the College of Home Economics Placement Office, Including Alumni Files
    - Wolff, Elizabeth, 1925-1933 (Box 63, Folder 48)
    - Wood, Bertha, 1916-1939 (Box 63, Folder 49)
    - Woolworth, Miriam, 1927, 1940 (Box 63, Folder 50)
    - Wooster, Rebecca, 1918-1919 (Box 63, Folder 51)
    - Worden, Lucile, 1928-1930 (Box 63, Folder 52)
      Married name Meeghan
    - Wright, Mary, 1916-1948 (Box 63, Folder 53)
      Married name Harvey
    - Wright, Norma, 1927-1956 (Box 63, Folder 54)
      Married name Stebbins
    - Wyckoff, Eilizabeth, 1923-1947 (Box 63, Folder 55)
    - Yoomans, Mildred, 1919-1926 (Box 63, Folder 56)
    - Zapf, Florence, 1938 (Box 63, Folder 57)
    - Zapf, Irene, 1922 (Box 63, Folder 58)
      Married name Witkop
    - Zoller, Marietta, 1933-1938 (Box 63, Folder 59)
      Married name Dickerson
    - Zuidema, Irene, 1932 (Box 63, Folder 60)
    - Graduate student files, 1915-1940 (Box 63, Folder 61)
      Contains corresponence to Flora Rose and Martha Van Rensselaer
    - Newspaper clippings, 1965-1966 (Box 63, Folder 62)
      Cooncerning Puerto Rico
    - Correspondence, articles, notes, 1965-1966 (Box 63, Folder 63)
      Concerning visit to Puerto Rico
    - Correspondence, memos, 1965-1968 (Box 63, Folder 64-67)
      Concerning the proposal to start an M.S. program in Home Economics in Puerto Rico
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 63, Folder 68)
      From Thomas Mangan of the New York State Education Department
    - Palatsky, Arlene, 1943 (Box 63, Folder 69)
      Concerning admission and being Jewish
    - Stroh, Laurel, 1949 (Box 63, Folder 70)
      Concerning "liberal attitude toward minority groups"
    - Stringham, Catherine, 1943 (Box 63, Folder 71)
      Concerning admission
    - Field Trips, 1951-1957 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Elementary Certification - Cornell, 1950-1969 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Secondary Certification, 1960-1969 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Home Economic Students Employed Part-Time at College, 1948-1966 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Beginning Jobs - Vocational Information, 1950-1969 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Alumni Lists, 1950-1969 (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Brochure, 1965 (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - Brochure, 1963 (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - Brochure, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - Alumni, 1955-1957, 1960-1969 (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - "This Job is Yours" - Publication put out by the Placement Office, 1946, 1948, 1952, 1960 (Box 69, Folder 23)
    - Letter from Esther Stocks to Alumnae, 1953-10 (Box 69, Folder 24)
  - College Reports
    - The Department of Home Economics Education, by Margaret Hutchins, 1946-1958 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Ad Hoc Committee Recommendations on College Study Report and Faculty discussion, 1967 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda concerning Dept. of Textiles and Clothing and Organizational Committee, 1967 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Reactions to Report, 1966-1967 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence concerning President's Committee, 1965-1968 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Response to College Study Report, Ad Hoc Committees, 1967-1968 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Dept. of Home Economics Education, Reports, 1958-1968 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Recommendations of an Ad Hoc Committee on the Status of Textiles and Clothing in a Reorganized College, 1968-10-22 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Organization of the College - Various Perspectives, 1969 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Dean Knapp's Remarks and Memoranda, Reports, 1968-1969, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Community Service Education - HSS, 1975-1985 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - College of Human Ecology - Memoranda, Reports, 1970-1979 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1959-1968 (Box 80)
    - Department Heads Meeting Minutes, 1962-1966 (Box 80)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1925-1943 (Box 81)
    - Department Heads Meeting Minutes, 1944-1962; 1966-1969 (Box 81)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1943-1959 (Box 82)
    - Academic Services Committee, 1969-1973 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Academic Status, 1974-1976 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Academic Standing Faculty Committee - Annual Reports, 1946-1961, 1963-1973 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Admissions - Annual Reports, 1947-1963 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Admissions - Annual Reports, 1965-1969 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Admissions - Annual Reports, 1969-1976 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Admissions Philosophy, Policies and Procedures of the Faculty Committee on Admissions, 1964, 1967 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Attrition - Reports, 1939-1950, 1939-1955, 1966-1973 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Certification of Home Economics Teachers, 1958-1968 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Proposed Program for Training Pre-Kindergarten and Kindergarten Teachers, 1968 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Communications - Publications Committee - Minutes and Annual Reports, 1950-1969 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Diversity, 1972-1973 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Extension Studies Committee, 1947-1950 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Graduate Education Committee - Annual Reports, 1969-1970, 1972-1973 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Graduate Fellowship Committee - Annual Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Grants Committee - Annual Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Mann Library Committee - Reports (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - 15 Nominations and Elections - Reports, 1948-1968 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Research Committee Reports, 1954-1973 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Student Faculty Committee - Reports, 1949-1969 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Study Concerning Change from Home Economics to Human Ecology, Refer to faculty meeting minutes from 1967 for discussions concerning the Final Report of the President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics. (Pages 4484-4547 and 4666-4707 in the bound issues of the Faculty Minutes.); For more records concerning the Reorganization of the College of Home Economics, see Henry Ricciuti's collection, #23-13-2551 and College of Human Ecology collection, #23-2-2817, box 106.; A copy of the final report of the President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics, December 1966, can be found in collection #23-13-2551, box 1, folders 1-7
    - Sex Discrimination Case - Cornell vs. 5 woman professors, 1975-1979 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Sample Research Proposals - Community Service Education - Sara Blackwell (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Horne Economics - Memoranda, Goals, Proposals, correspondence, Minutes, 1961-1965 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Minutes, Memoranda, 1965 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - External Consultants, 1966 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Minutes, Reports, 1966 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Progress Reports, Memoranda Reports to the Committee by people outside of Cornell, Minutes, 1966 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Memoranda, Minutes, 1966 (Box 78, Folder 9-10)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Reports, Memoranda, Discussion of final report, 1966 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Memoranda, Correspondence, Committee Reports, 1966-1967-05 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Final Report of the President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics, 1966-12 (Box 78, Folder 13)
- Series II. Cooperation of the College with Governmental, Educational, and Private Organizations, 1916-1959
  - Government, National, New York State
    - Government Groups - National - Land Grant College Association, 1922-1932 (Box 10, Folder 32-36)
    - Government Groups - National - Land Grant College Association, 1933-1940 (Box 10, Folder 37-40)
    - Government Groups - National - Land Grant College Association, 1941-1943 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Government Groups - National - Land Grant College Association Nutrition Bill, 1943-1945 (Box 10, Folder 42-43)
    - Government Groups - Land Grant - Home Economics Division (Historical), 1946-1954 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Research Advisory Committee - Land Grant - (next meeting), 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - National Council of Parent Education, 1926-1929 (Box 10, Folder 46-47)
    - National Council of Parent Education, 1930-1931 (Box 10, Folder 48-51)
    - National Council of Parent Education, 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
    - National Council of Youth Administration, 1935-1936 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
    - National Council of Youth Administration, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 8-12)
    - U.S.D.A. - policies, 1918, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - U.S.D.A. - correspondence, 1908-1920 (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
    - U.S.D.A. - Bureau of Home Economics Dietary Studies, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - U.S.D.A. - Bureau of Home Economics, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Origin of Bureau of Home Economics, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - U.S. Department of Education - Federal Board of Vocational Education, 1926-1927 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - U.S. Department of Labor - correspondence, 1913, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - U.S. War Department Service, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - W.P.A. - Rural Rehabilitation, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - W.P.A. - Rural Settlement, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous U.S. government groups - correspondence, 1908-1920 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Desmond Joint Legislative Committee on Nutrition, 1943-1946 (Box 11, Folder 25-26)
    - New York State Department of Agriculture, correspondence, 1908-1915 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - New York State Agricultural Advisory Commission: Martha Van Rensselaer, 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - New York State Advisory Committee: Flora Rose, 1930-1934 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Farmers' Institutes, 1905-1919 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Farmers' Institute - Women's Institutes, 1906-1922 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Farmers' Institute - Women's - clippings, 1903-1907 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Women's Institutes encapsulated poster, 1907 (Box 64)
      Speakers were Martha Van Rensselaer, Helen Wells, Matie Dann, and Gertrude Gray
    - New York State Council of Rural Women, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - New York State Department of Education - correspondence, 1907-1918 (Box 11, Folder 34-35)
    - New York State Department of Education - Bureau of Home Economics Education, 1941-1943 (Box 11, Folder 36-37)
    - New York State Department of Education - Bureau of Home Economics Education, 1922-1938 (Box 11, Folder 38-44)
    - New York State Department of Education - Bureau of Home Economics Education, 1944-1946 (Box 11, Folder 45-46)
    - New York State Department of Education - general, 1941-1946 (Box 11, Folder 47-49)
    - New York State Commissioner of Education Graves - correspondence with Martha Van Rensselaer, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - New York State Department of Education Child Guidance, 1930-1932 (Box 11, Folder 51-52)
    - New York State Department of Education Home Report, 1934-1937 (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - New York State Flood Relief Program, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - New York State Food Commissioner, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - New York State Food Supply Commission, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - New York State Nutrition Committee, 1937-1949 (Box 12, Folder 4-7)
    - New York State Department~ of Health - correspondence, 1911-1921 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - New York State Department of Labor - Children's Bureau, 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - New York State Joint Legislative Economy Committee, 1942-08 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - New York State Joint Legislative Committee on Imitation Milk Products and Problems, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - New York State departments - correspondence, 1903-1913 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Government Groups - Local
    - Cooperative Program between College and Nassau County, 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Tompkins County Development Association, 1935-1937 (Box 12, Folder 14-15)
  - Private Groups
    - Associated Country Women of the World, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 16-18)
    - Associated Country Women of the World, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Private Groups - International
    - Agricultural missions Foundation, 1931-1945 (Box 12, Folder 20-22)
    - International Congress of Farm Women and the International Sunshine Society correspondence, 1910-1911 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Private Groups National
    - American Country Life Association, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - American Home Economics Association correspondence, 1921 (Box 12, Folder 25-29)
    - American Home Economics Association Lake Placid Conference - correspondence, including letters to and from Annie and Melvil Dewey, 1903-1915 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - American Home Economics Association, 1916-1930 (Box 12, Folder 31-34)
    - American Home Economics Association, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - American Home Economics Association, 1930-1940 (Box 12, Folder 36-39)
    - American Home Economics Association, 1940-1946 (Box 12, Folder 40-43)
    - American Red Cross - correspondence, 1917-1921 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Association for Childhood Education, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Better Homes in America Organization, 1922-1935 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Child Health organization of America, 1920-1931 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Foods Facts Foundation, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - League of Women Voters, 1927-1930 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - League of Women Voters - correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Mothers' Assembly - correspondence, 1909-1914 (Box 12, Folder 51-52)
    - National Country Life Association - correspondence, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Girl Scouts, 1923-1927 (Box 12, Folder 54-55)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs - correspondence, 1909-1915 (Box 12, Folder 56-58)
    - Grange - correspondence, 1904-1928 (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - Women's National Farm and Garden Association, 1931-1936 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Woman's Christian Temperance Union (W.C.T.U.) - correspondence, 1907-1920 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) - correspondence, 1907-1920 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - National organizations - correspondence, 1907-1921 (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
  - Private Groups: Regional
    - Miscellaneous regional groups - correspondence, 1912-1915 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Private Groups: State
    - New York State Agricultural Society, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - New York State Council of Rural Women, 1931-1941 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Home Bureau Creed and Home Bureau Song (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Original Home Bureau Creed (Mapcase-item Frame 1)
    - Home Bureau - union with Home Economics, 1917-1920 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Farm and Home Bureaus: correspondence on problems of individual Bureaus, 1915-1921 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureaus, 1925-1933 (Box 13, Folder 16-20)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureaus - and the College Marketing Program, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 21-24)
    - Farm and Home Bureau - recommended constitution, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureaus, 1934-1940 (Box 13, Folder 26-28)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureaus - correspondence, 1940-1946 (Box 13, Folder 29-32)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureau - Reports, 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 33-37)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureau Reports, 1943-1946 (Box 13, Folder 38-41)
    - Home Bureau Federation Publicity Workshop, 1950-09 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Farm-Home Bureau - Extension - realignment, 1953-1955 (Box 13, Folder 43-44)
    - State Federation of Home Bureaus Handbook, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - New York State Federation of Presidents of Women's Educational Organizations, 1921-1934 (Box 13, Folder 46-50)
    - Conference Board of Women's Organizations in New York State, 1935-1943 (Box 13, Folder 51-55)
    - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs - correspondence, 1901-1921 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
    - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs, 1932-1936 (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
    - New York State Home Economics Association, 1922-1954 (Box 14, Folder 6-8)
    - New York State Home Economics Clubs, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - New York League of Women Voters, 1936-1943 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - New York State Social Hygiene Society - correspondence, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous State Organizations - correspondence, 1903-1925 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Private Groups: Local
    - Ithaca P.T.A. Study Group, 1935-1939 (Box 14, Folder 13-14)
    - Local Library Organizations - correspondence, 1911-1912 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Local Organizations - correspondence, 1906-1921 (Box 14, Folder 16-17)
    - Visitors to College of Home Economics, 1926-1959 (Box 14, Folder 18-21)
  - Educational Groups: Universities and Colleges
    - University of the State of New York, correspondence, 1918-1920 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - New York State School of Agriculture, (Long Island) correspondence, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Other New York State (government supported) Colleges, correspondence, 1906-1917 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Other State Universities, correspondence, 1905-1921 (Box 14, Folder 25-28)
    - Miscellaneous colleges and universities, A-M, correspondence, 1906-1920 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous colleges and universities, N-Z, correspondence, 1910-1931 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - University of Illinois - correspondence, 1903-1920 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Merrill-Palmer School, 1922-1934, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 33-36)
    - Simmons College - correspondence, 1909-1921 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Traphagen School of Fashion (1680 Broadway, New York, New York), 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous educational groups
    - Public and private grade and high schools - correspondence, 1908-1921 (Box 14, Folder 39-41)
    - George Jr. Republic - correspondence, 1910-1918 (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - American Association of University Women, 1935-1940 (Box 14, Folder 43-45)
    - American Association of University Women, 1941-1946 (Box 14, Folder 46-48)
    - Conference Board of Women's Educational organizations (in New York State), 1920-1941 (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Educational Groups in other countries - correspondence, 1903-1920 (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - Miscellaneous Educational Groups, 1906-1920 (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Northeast Region Home Economics Administrators (minutes), 1948-1964 (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary School - Part B of Questionnaire Guide for Institutional Self-Evaluation, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary School - Part B. of Questionnaire Guide - Copies of Original Answers By Sub-Committees (1-19) (Box 14, Folder 54-55)
    - Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary School - Part B of Questionnaire Guide - Copies of Original Answers by Sub-Committees (20-33) (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Institutes and Conferences held at the College
    - State Committee on the New York State College of Home Economics Conference, Ithaca, 1927-05 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
    - Cornell P.T.A. Institute, 1938-1946 (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
    - Nutrition Conferences, Institutes, 1940-1949 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - New York State Nutrition Institute, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - New York State Nutrition Institute - correspondence, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 9-10)
    - Rural Urban Forum, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Conference on Home Safety for Supervising Public Health Nurses, 1944-05 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Work Simplification Project of the General Education Board, 1945-01 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Van Rensselaer - Rose Faculty Seminar and Lecture Series, 1947, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
    - Van Rensselaer - Rose Series, 1945-1955 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Conference of New York State Association of Future Homemakers of America, 1948-05 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Conference for Homemaking Teachers, 1948-1953 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Home Management Conference, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Institute on International Education in Home Economics, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Series III. All-College Activities
  - Receptions
    - Campus guests and guest lecturers, 1904-1915 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Report of Dean Vincent's Reception, 1946-11 (Box 15, Folder 21-22)
    - Reception for the Dean, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Reception for Miss Canoyer, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Cooperation with College of Agriculture
    - College of Agriculture: Abstracts of Faculty Meetings, 1917-1918 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - College of Agriculture Business office, 1929-1937 (Box 15, Folder 26-28)
    - College of Agriculture Policies, 1915-1931 (Box 15, Folder 29-30)
    - Planning for Mann Library, 1944-1948 (Box 15, Folder 31-32)
    - Relationship between College of Home Economics and Rural Education Department, 1941-1946 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Cooperation with Rural Sociology Department, 1912-1929 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Sub-committee on social work, 1929-1946 (Box 15, Folder 35-36)
    - College of Agriculture Publications office, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Proposed Conference Center, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Cooperation with other Divisions of the University
    - University Board of Trustees, 1926-1929 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - University Library Board, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Participation in Cornell University Activities
    - Extracts from minutes of meetings of Executive Committee and Board of Trustees, 1952-1954 (Box 15, Folder 41-43)
    - Extracts from minutes of meetings of Executive Committee and Board of Trustees, 1955-1958 (Box 15, Folder 44-45)
    - University Convocations, 1919 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - University Policies, 1913-1930 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Inaugurations - Farrand, Day, Malott, 1921-1951 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - Cornell University Semi-Centennial Celebration, 1918-1919 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - SUNY Materials
    - State University of New York President Alvin C. Ewich, 1949-1951 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - SUNY - State Education Department Bureau of Home Economics Education, 1952-1954 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - SUNY - Committees - Personnel Policies, 1950-1953 (Box 15, Folder 52-53)
    - SUNY - questionnaires, 1949-1952 (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - SUNY materials, 1949-1950 (Box 15, Folder 55-56)
    - SUNY and Cornell University, relations with, 1949-1952 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - SUNY Master Plan for Community Colleges and 4 year Colleges for the State (Box 16, Folder 2-4)
  - Farmers' Week and Farm and Home Week
    - Farm and Home Week: Early History (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Farmers Institute and Farmers Week - Homemakers Conference, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Farmers Institute and Farmers Week - Homemakers Conference, 1910-1913 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Farmers Institute and Farmers Week - Homemakers Conference, 1915-1917 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Farmers Institute and Farmers Week - Homemakers Conference-clippings, 1915-1917 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Farmers Institute and Farmers Week - Homemakers Conference - photographs (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Farmers Week - Homemakers Conference, 1918-1921 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Farmers Week - Homemakers Conference, 1924, 1928-1930 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Farm and Home Week, 1931-1932 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Farm and Home Week Speakers, 1930-1942 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Farm and Home Week, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Farm and Home Week, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Farm and Home Week, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Farm and Home Week, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 18-21)